Guide to the Rice University Gilbert and Sullivan Society collection, 1950-1967 UA 259
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Gilbert and Sullivan Society collection
1950-1967
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 259
2 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Records of the Gilbert & Sullivan Society, a group of Faculty members and their wives who staged a number of productions in the 1950s and 1960s.
Historical Sketch
The Gilbert and Sullivan Society was an amatuer theater company composed of Rice University faculty, staff and their spouses. The group organized an annual, free performance of a Gilbert and Sullivan operetta each spring between 1951 and 1967. Plays were funded by faculty and supporter donations, and featured two performances per year; one for students and the other for faculty. The primary goal of the group, in addition to the production of the operettas, was to foster community and relationships between faculty members.
Scope and Contents
Records of the Gilbert & Sullivan Society, a group of Faculty members and their wives who staged a number of productions in the 1950s and 1960s. The records are made up laregly of tapes and publications of these productions, and dates run from 1950-1966. Materials include 15 reel tapes; programs; newspaper clippings; 1 poster; LP records; notices; scenery plans.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 1 stored onsite in vault at Woodson Research Center. Boxes 2-4 stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to the archives in 1992.
Index Terms
Subjects
College students -- Texas; Theatrical productions; Theater
Document Types
notes; audiotapes; programs (documents)
- Series I: Recordings, 166300
  - Trial by Jury, LP record of society production, 1951; 154605 (Box 1)
  - Iolanthe: 5 reel-to-reel tapes, 1953; 154606 (Box 2)
  - The Sorcerer: 6 reel-to-reel tapes, 1954; 154607 (Box 2)
  - The Pirates of Penzance: 4 reel-to-reel tapes, 1955; 154608 (Box 2)
- Series II: Programs, notes, planning, scores, 166301
  - Invitations, 1951-53; 154609 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1951-66; 154610 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personal notes, 1951-65; 154611 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notices, 1951-67; 154612 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1952-53, 1998; 154613 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Trial by Jury and Cox and Box program, Trial by Jury score, 1956; 155867 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Trial by Jury planning and rehearsal notes, 1951; 155868 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Mikado Acts I & II stage scenery renderings, by Anderson Todd, 1964; 154614 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Mikado negatives, 1964; 154615 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vocal Score: Iolanthe, or The Peer and the Peri (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Vocal Score: Princess Ida, or, Castle Adamant (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Vocal Score: The Sorcerer (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Vocal Score: The Pirates of Penzance (Box 4, Item 4)
  - Vocal Score: Trial by Jury (Box 4, Item 5)
- Series III: Oversize, 154616
  - 14x22 in. poster for Iolanthe, 1953; 154617 (Map-drawer 80)
  - 2 stage scenery plan postes for Arcadia and Castle, 154618 (Map-drawer 80)
  - Flag from The Pirates of Penzance, n.d.; 154619